DANNY PAGE

Oakton, Virginia | daniel.w.page@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/danielwpage

SUMMARY

A diligent and technically proficient staff software developer and data engineer, specializing in web applications, data analytics, machine learning, A/B testing, and statistical analysis. Established capabilities in engineering, statistical modeling, troubleshooting, and project management. Utilizes strong interpersonal and communications skills to assess client requirements and business practices, facilitate meetings and team discussions, and guide and mentor associates. An analytical and results-oriented top performer, who contributes to identifying opportunities to address client needs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, Flask, Django, Ruby on Rails, Go, JavaScript, SQL, Spark, Scala

<u>Databases</u>: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Oracle, SQLite, AWS Dynamo

Other Technologies: AWS S3, Git, Apache, NGINX, Jenkins, Chef, Airflow, Hadoop

Machine Learning & Data Analysis: AWS SageMaker, TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn, Tableau, MLOps

Other Skills: Agile, Scrum, Pull Request Reviews, Mentorship, Documentation, Presenting

EDUCATION

WESTERN GOVERNORS UNIVERSITY, Remote, M.S., Data Analytics, 2020
HIGH POINT UNIVERSITY, High Point, North Carolina, B.S., Computer Science and Mathematics, 2009

EXPERIENCE

INDEED, Oakton, Virginia (Remote)

Staff Software Engineer, 2022-2023

- Utilized Python and AWS SageMaker to drive machine learning data pipelines.
- Employed Scala, Spark, and Hadoop to join large datasets together for analyzing performance of machine learning models in affecting the funnel of positive outcomes for applicants
- Worked across multiple teams to facilitate time-critical migrations without downtime
- Wrote design documents for initiative planning and getting buy-in on technical solutions

NERDWALLET, San Francisco, California & Oakton, Virginia (Remote)

Technology Lead, 2022

Senior Software Engineer, 2019-2022

- Utilized Go, Dynamo, Airflow, and AWS SageMaker to drive machine learning data pipelines.
- Employed Dynamo and APIs to deliver batch-insights and SageMaker end points for real-time insights.
- Developed APIs to support mobile and web applications.
- Implemented features on Python, Flask, and PostgreSQL stack.
- Led recruiting outreach for NerdWallet Engineering social media accounts and blog.

UPCOUNSEL, San Francisco, California

Full-Stack and Data Engineer, 2018-2019

- Implemented features on Ruby on Rails, MongoDB, and Backbone JS stack.
- Improved database efficiency on MongoDB and PostgreSQL for ETL and data warehouse retrieval.
- Created and maintained ETL and data processing scripts in Python.
- Mentored new employees on Git processes and Python.
- Wrote automated tests for quality control with RSpec.
- Increased user engagement and revenue by conducting A/B testing with Google Optimize and Ruby.
- Participated in recruitment by interviewing new candidates.

CAPTERRA (GARTNER DIGITAL MARKETS), Arlington, Virginia

Full Stack Software Engineer, 2016-2018

- Implemented features on Ruby on Rails, Oracle, and JQuery stack.
- Designed reporting suite within internal RoR app, writing SQL queries to support reports.
- Wrote automated tests for quality control with RSpec.
- Conducted A/B testing with Optimizely to increase user engagement and revenue.

SOCIALCODE, Washington, D.C.

Back-End Software Engineer, 2014-2016

- Coded features on Python and Django data platform to build internal applications.
- Implemented connections to Facebook and Twitter Advertising APIs, and kept up with breaking changes.
- Developed internal APIs, including creating schema, code testing, and user feedback.
- Wrote automated tests for quality control and Celery tasks for automated crawling.

TRANSLŌC, Raleigh, North Carolina

Back-End Developer/Data Analyst, 2013-2014

- Created vehicle management features in Python and Django.
- Structured data collection and storage in MySQL and created Transit dashboards.
- Developed internal metrics to help customers identify actionable improvements for transit agencies.
- Scaled MySQL and MongoDB databases as the company grew in scale.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

WASHINGTON SPIRIT, Germantown, Maryland, **Statistics and Technical Advisor**, 2015. Collected passing and possession statistics for every game. Created visualizations and apps that supported coach and club's internal media objectives. Advised on technical issues that supported the club's analysis and customer outreach.

DATA MEANING, Washington, D.C., **Analytics Contractor**, 2012. Consulted with clients to create MicroStrategy dashboards to track profits and shipping rates. Created metrics for measurement of monthly, quarterly, and yearly reports to monitor progress. Determined correlations and forecasts, using hotel customer ratings to determine future revenue.

MDEVERYWHERE, INC., Durham, North Carolina, **Ruby on Rails Contractor**, 2012. Developed API in Ruby on Rails flagship application to interface with medical practices and hospitals. Created reporting to measure insurance claim successes. Implemented RSpec automated code-testing protocols to minimize production server downtime.

KNACKEO, Raleigh, North Carolina, **Co-Founder and CEO**, 2011-2012. Established database schema in PostgreSQL, and developed Ruby on Rails application. Worked with teachers and students continually to iterate on design of product. Integrated analytics and A/B testing to best determine conversions and adoption.

MICROSTRATEGY, McLean, Virginia, **Education Consultant**, 2010-2011. Shaped MicroStrategy training for various verticals, including entertainment, banking, and retail. Worked with customers to determine best metrics for success in the company. Wrote training manuals and delivered presentations in person and online.

AOL, Sterling, Virginia, **Junior Software Engineer**, 2010. Developed features for AOL Desktop Browser in C++, and worked with QA to troubleshoot bugs. Researched future features for further AOL browser innovations.

MICROSTRATEGY, McLean, Virginia, **Technical Support Engineer**, 2009-2010. Earned MicroStrategy Certified Engineer certification to design customized reporting solutions. Assisted customers in identifying solutions to create ideal reports and dashboards. Documented errors for developers to accurately fix problems and enhance customer experiences.